Andriy Kotko React developer

in linkedin.com/in/kotkoa
github.com/Kotkoa
Telegram: @Kotkoa

kotkoa@gmail.com
+34-647185406
Valencia, Spain

Summary

Frontend Developer, with 6 years of experience in web applications at fintech, social media, and securities. Led the development and launch investment application, handling over 50,000 user transactions monthly and enhancing transaction processing speed by 30%. Effectively collaborate across departments to create tailored, business centric web solutions.

Technical Skills

React.js, Typescript, Vite, Next.js, Apollo GraphQl, Rest API, Jotai, Mobx, react-context, Redux, CSS-modules, Tailwind, Material-UI, Radix-UI, Jest, Cypress, Yup-validation, Figma, Storybook, Drag-n-Drop, TV Lightweight Charts, JSON Forms, Github, Gitlab, CI/CD practices, ESLint, Prettier

Experience

Human Capital Exchange, Los Angeles - (Remote)

Sep 2022 - Feb 2024

Senior Frontend Developer - Contractor

Joined the <u>HCX</u> team as a contractor to enhance a tech team of 12 developers for maintaining an app of investment application aimed at connecting investors, sponsors, and talents on one platform.

- Streamlined account setup with multi-form flows for different users, integrating JSON Forms, Yup validation, and Apollo GraphQL, improving form submission efficiency by 90%.
- Updated API in partnership with the backend team, adding features and fixing bugs, which boosted server performance by 20% and accelerated feature deployment by 25%.
- Streamlined the system by removing 3 blockchain libraries, shifting to bank transactions, and introducing debit/credit card and bank account features, reducing operation costs by 30%.
- Orchestrated the integration of DocuSign for in-app application signings, streamlining the process and reducing turnaround time by 40%, ensuring compliance with stringent KYC regulations and legal requirements.
- Led the integration process for newly hired developers, reducing onboarding time from one month to 1 week.
- Integrated Jest and Cypress with CI/CD for automated user flow testing, reducing manual QA time by 25%.
- Enhanced Material-UI global theme, streamlining common styles to save 68 workdays on component creation and saving the company 8000\$.

Technologies Used: React.js, Typescript, Jotai, Material-UI, Figma, GraphQL, React Native, DnD kit, TV Chart Library, Nx Monorepo, Next.js, WordPress, Jest, Cypress, Go.

Yara International, Singapore - (Remote)

Apr 2021 - Jun 2022

UI Developer

Hired to the design system's team of 10 developers to enhance the usability and accessibility of <u>Yara International's</u> design system.

- Added over 10 new components to the design system, fully refactoring existing ones, and improving accessibility to meet global standards, and boosting compliance by 44%.
- Created a novel token system, enhancing design-to-code efficiency by 32%, leading to smoother design adoption and uniformity across projects.

 Developed closely with designers to refine and implement component designs, discussing the overall look of the Storybook theme.

Technologies Used: React.js, TypeScript, Storybook, Figma, Design System, Radix-Ui, Girthub, React Native.

Root Name System (RNS), Singapore - (Remote)

Jan 2020 - Dec 2021

Frontend Developer

Maintained the innovative digital identity platform RNS to issue digital IDs for Palau's digital residence, and led the international tech team in creating applications from scratch.

- Spearheaded the creation of 3 landing pages, 2 web apps, and 35 email HTML templates for user subscriptions, enhancing user engagement, and integrating new features such as id verification, TypeScript migration, and Jest test coverage.
- Refined MaterialUI components to styled components, enhancing UI flexibility and responsiveness; decreased app load time by 40% and elevated user experience satisfaction ratings by 15%.
- Simplified codebase by transitioning from Redux, Redux-toolkit to MobX, reducing boilerplate by 40% and enhancing maintainability.
- Integrated internationalization using i18n, expanding market reach by enabling content localization for 12 new languages, which led to a 28% increase in global user engagement.

Technologies Used: React.js, Next.js, Tailwind, Redux, Mobx, SASS, Mobx, Python, Blockchain, S3.

Freelance Javascript Developer, Tenerife, Spain - (Remote)

Jan 2018 - Dec 2020

Fullstack Developer

• Collaborated with the design team to develop HTML markup templates, driving a 30% increase in mobile conversions and a 20% decrease in cart abandonment rates.

Technologies Used: HTML, CSS, WordPress, Joomla, GoogleAnalitycs, Seo-optimisation.

Education

Instrument Engineering

Sevastopol Technical State University, Ukraine